Welcome to our Channel today we are
going to discuss important question from
CBC class 10 mathematics specifically
trometry let us consider a question if 3
c a = 4 check whether 1 - tan a / 1 + t²
a = cos² a - sin
a to solve this let consider a right
angle triangle ABC with the right angle
at B give given that t a given that 3 C
= 4 Rite the equation c a = 4
by3 we know the
relation tan a = 4 by3 since t a equal
to opposite side ided by Adent side we
have tan a = to BC / by AB now let's now
let's substitute the value BC = to 3K
units and a = 4K units where K is a real
positive number we need to calculate
hypotenuse AC using Pythagorean theorem
AC
s a² = to a² + BC squ after substituting
the value AC = to 5K
unit now we have hypotenuse value so we
can calculate sin a and cos a sin AAL to
opposite side divid hypot which is equal
to BC / AC with 3x 4 similarly cos a
equal to Adent side/ hypotenuse which is
equal to a / AC with value 4 by 5 to
check the given equation let consider
the left hand side LHS 1 - tan S A / 1 +
t s
a substituting the value of T A we got
got 1 - 3x 4² 1 + 3x
4² you simplified 7 by 25 now let us
consider the right hand side rhs cos² A-
sin S A substituting the value of cos a
and sin a we got 4x 3² - 3x b² which is
Al which is simplified to 7 by
25 since LHS equal to rhs
we have proved that given equation is
correct this is the one of the easiest
way to solve this problem